<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>rover-project on Aaron Ogle</title><link>/tags/rover-project/</link><description>Recent content in rover-project on Aaron Ogle</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/rover-project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rover Project: Update 3</title><link>/2021/07/04/rover-project-update-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/07/04/rover-project-update-3/</guid><description>Finally a more eventful update!
Last time I worked with building parts in CAD I was using solidworks or AutoCAD. I have no desire to buy either one of those right now plus I need something that will run on linux. So started investing some time into learning my way around FreeCAD.
Creating first iteration of the wheel 50mm radius for a 10cm/100mm diameter wheel
3mm thick
Based on the specs of the motor:</description></item><item><title>Rover Project: Update 2</title><link>/2021/07/04/rover-project-update-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/07/04/rover-project-update-2/</guid><description>So the robot parts sat in my closet for a few months. I kind of forgot to order the parts.
Recently realized I really need to disconnect more fully from work in my off hours. When your hobby includes coding and in same language as you write for work.. Its a bit harder to keep your brain from making that jump to thinking about work.
So i&amp;rsquo;ve been on the look out for new hobbies.</description></item><item><title>Rover Project: Update 1</title><link>/2021/07/04/rover-project-update-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/07/04/rover-project-update-1/</guid><description>Parts came in!
Finally got time to work on it again. We wired everything up.
We gathered up some cardboard. We found something to trace and cut out 4 wheels. (you&amp;rsquo;ll notice this is defintely a deviation from the original sketch. But this was insisted on once the additional motors were spotted).
We also put together the transmitter on another breadboard
Now if you do electronics seriously at all you&amp;rsquo;ll probably notice straight away two different issues.</description></item><item><title>Rover Project</title><link>/2021/07/04/rover-project/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/07/04/rover-project/</guid><description>My family is very STEM oriented. I grew up learning hands on at home. Taking things apart. Questioning how things worked and eventually learning how to actually fix those things I took apart. As much as possible we&amp;rsquo;re trying to encourage this for our kids.
They are pretty fortunate as they have good examples of this on both sides of the family. So they come by their curiousity about the world around them very naturally.</description></item></channel></rss>